The most dangerous man in the world. He's about to expose
the CIA, the FBI, the KGB ... and himself.
Hopscotch is a comedy, adventure film directed by Ronald Neame.
When CIA operative Miles Kendig deliberately lets KGB agent
Yaskov get away, his boss threatens to retire him.
Kendig beats him to it, however, destroying his own records and traveling to Austria where he
begins work on a memoir that will expose all his former agency's covert practices.
The CIA catches wind of the book and sends other agents after him,
initiating a frenetic game of cat and mouse that spans the globe.
Miles Kendig, played by Walter Matthau.
Isobel, played by Glenda Jackson.
Jack Cutter, played by Sam Waterston.
Myerson, played by Ned Beatty.
Yaskov, played by Herbert Lom.
Ross, played by David Matthau.
Hopscotch is a 1980 American comedy spy film directed by Ronald Neame and starring
Walter Matthau, Glenda Jackson, Sam Waterston, Ned Beatty and Herbert Lom.
The screenplay was written by Bryan Forbes and Brian
Garfield, based on Garfield's 1975 novel.
Garfield took the title of his book from the children's playground game, "wherein a player has
to retrieve 'an elusive object' while hopping on a sidewalk from space to space.
One false step or clumsy move could mean falling and landing on one's backside."
Matthau's performance received a
Golden Globe nomination for Best Actor – Motion Picture Musical or Comedy at the 38th Golden Globe Awards.
In 2002, the Criterion Collection released the film on DVD,
followed by a 2K restoration on Blu-ray in 2017.
The film explores themes of central intelligence agency (cia),
based on novel or book, england, germany, spy.
The tone is lighthearted.